RG 002:025, Commission to Study Reorganization and Unification of the Courts
Connecticut State Library
Commission to Study Reorganization and Unification of the Courts records
1958-1978, bulk 1974-1975
1974-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Commission to Study Reorganization and Unification of the Courts
.5 cubic feet
The 1973 session of the Connecticut General Assembly created this Commission to draft legislation to be presented to the 1974 session of the General Assembly.
RG002_025_COURT
1995-066
Historical Note
The 1973 session of the Connecticut General Assembly created this Commission to draft legislation to be presented to the 1974 session of the General Assembly. The Commission staff was directed to compile reportsd and recommendations of the Judicial Council, the Chief Court Administrator and the American and Connecticut Bar Associations as well as thoe of other knowledgeable organizations. Reports from other states which had conducted similar studies were also obtained. The Connecticut Citizens for Judicial Modernization conducted surveys concerning utilization of courtroom time, the quality of courtroom facilities and their use, and evaluations of the effect of various proposals for structural reorganization. The Commission also heald public hearings throughtout the State, mailed questionnaires to all people involved in the court system, and opened all Commission meetings to the public. The Commission met on a weekly basis to consider items such as court structure, court administration, prosecution and defense services, judicial selection, court financing, plea bargaining, judicial compensation, judicial retirement, and disciplinary action for judges.
Source: Final Report of the Commission to Study and Draft Legislation for the Reorganization an Unification of the Courts, March 1, 1974.
Scope and Content
Includes reports, meeting notices and agendas, correspondence, questionnaires, testimony, and background and resource material.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Connecticut. Commission to Study Reorganization and Unification of the Courts; Court administration -- Connecticut; Courts -- Connecticut; Justice, Administration of -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Agendas; Minutes; News clippings; Press releases; Minutes
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1958-1978, bulk 1974-1975
  - Final Report of the Commission to Study adn Draft Legislation for the Reorganization and Unification of the Courts to the 1974 Session of the General Assembly, 1974 March 1 (Box 1)
    This report is not in a folder.
    A copy is available at
  - Conn. - 1 tier court position statements, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Conn. - Court system report, southeastern, Conn., 1971 (Box 1)
  - Conn. - Public hearing, Hall of House, State Capitol, 1974 September 23 (Box 1)
  - 1974 appointments commission, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Advisory subcommittee membership and addresses, 1974 October 24 (Box 1)
  - Meeting notices, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Memos, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - United States - 1 tier court status report, 1974 September 25 (Box 1)
  - Court revision material - 1 tier, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Press materials regarding 1 tier, 1973-1975, undated (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Bar Association court reorganization questionnaire, 1974 September 23 (Box 1)
  - Meeting notices and agendas, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Articles and editorials regarding reform, 1974, undated (Box 1)
  - Legislation, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - List of bar associations, circa 1974 (Box 1)
  - Background and resource materials, 1958-1974 (Box 1)
  - Testomony, 1974, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Conn. - Constitutionality 1 tier court system, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - Agendas, 1974 (Box 1)
  - American Bar Association court reorganization standards, 1973-1976, undated (Box 1)
  - Public hearing, Justice Green, D.C.; Justice Carter, Illinois, 1974 November 12 (Box 1)